Let's implement the logic to pass the real ingredients we picked on the checkout container. I'll do this
Kontrol konteyneri iin aldmz gerek malzemeleri pasta mantna uygulamaya koyalm Buray Bergere
here in my burger builder component obviously where I push to the checkout page. There
Boulder bileeninde burada yapacam, tabii ki orada deme sayfasna ittiim yer.
I now want to push a javascript object
imdi bir javascript nesnesi itmek istiyorum.
where I'll set path name to /Checkout but where I then can specify a search parameter, a search query
yi Profesr izgi kontrol denilen ama dedi nerede bir cevirici maddeyi gemek istedigim bir arama parametresi
which is how I want to pass the ingredients.
veya bir arama sorusu belirleyebilirsiniz dedi.
Now for that I of course somehow need to encode my ingredients into such a search query,
imdi bunun iin tabii ki bir ekilde malzemelerimi byle bir arama sorgusuna kodlamam gerekiyor.
how can I do that?
Bunu nasl yapabilirim.
I will create a new constant which I'll name queryParams, the name is up to you of course and this will be an
elbette size kalm ve balangta bo bir dizi olacak yeni bir sabiti deneyeceim.
empty array initially but
Bir isim sorgusu ebeveyn adnn
then I want to add elements to that array, I'll do this with a for loop and i'll loop through all the properties
Daha sonra, bir for dngs ve bu durum bileenindeki tm zellikleri ierecek ekilde doodles dizilimine
in this.state.ingredients so in the ingredients I have. Now I will push
elemanlar eklemenizi istiyorum, bylece imdi Porche'yi kullanacam ierikler.
each ingredient to this queryParams array
Ebeveyn dizisini tanmlamak iin her madde.
but there I will use a little helper method which is provided by javascript, encodeURIComponent,
Ancak javascript ve kod tarafndan salanan kk bir yardmc yntem kullanacam.
which simply encodes my elements such that they can be used in the URL,
Benim elerimi U r l'de kullanlabilecek ekilde kodlayan bir bileen sizsiniz.
this is relevant for whitespace and so on.
Bu, boluk iin olduka kt ve benzeri.
There I'll use the property name I, which wouldn't need encoding in my case because it will work like
mlkiyet adna kodlamaya ihtiya duymayacak ekilde kullanlyorlar, nk salam ve benzeri ekilde alacaklar iin benim durumumda.
that salad and so on,
Hepsi benim
these are all non-critical elements.
Bunlarn hepsi kritik olmayan unsurlardr.
Then add an equal sign because we have key equals something in queryParams and then I'll also encode the
Ardndan eit iaret ekleyin, nk anahtar eit bir ey sorgu parantezine eittir ve daha sonra deeri
value. Again,
tekrar kodlar.
this wouldn't really be needed here because the value is just a number which is non-critical
Burada gerekten gerek duyulmaz, nk deer yalnzca kritik olmayan bir saydr.
but here I'll then use this state ingredients for the key we're currently at.
Ancak burada, u anda bulunduumuz decie iin bu devlet ieriklerini kullanacam.
So i is the key, these are the property names in my ingredients in the end just
Bu yzden aklda kalan mlkiyet isimleri anahtarna sordum, sonunda.
and here I'm setting property name equal to well the value for that property name.
Ve burada mlk adn bu mlk adnn deerine eit olarak ayarlarm.
So this is an array which now just has a couple of strings which is property name equal property value.
Yani bu, sadece mlkiyet ad eit mlk deeri olan birka dizeye sahip bir dizidir.
Now this array of strings is what I want to join with the & sign.
imdi bu dizgi dizisi, biti iaretiyle katlmak istediim ey.
So I'll add a queryString constant here where I'll use my queryParams array, call the join method
Bu yzden burada birletirme yntemi olarak adlandrlan ve son iaretiyle gsteren sorgu
and join it with an & sign and then finally, I want to attach it here with ? and then
parantez dizisini kullanacam bir sorgu dizesi sabiti ekleyeceim ve nihayet burada questionmark ve daha sonra sadece benim olan
my queryString which is just my string of well ingredients. Let me save this and let's see if that works,
sorgu dizesi eklemeye baladm yilik mihverleri biriktirmeme izin ver Bu iler ballerer Polder'a dnp
if I go back to the burger builder
dnmediini grmyor mu?
and yes the links aren't good links, they are still the old links which reload the app but it's fine for now.
Ve evet balantlar tanrlar deil, halen derin ama ince olan eski eylerdir.
So let's build a burger now, click order now and click continue
imdi imdi Sipari gibi bir burger yapalm ve devam etmeye devam edelim.
and you can see that I do pass it on like this in the URL.
Ve grdnz gibi bunu UR l'de olduu gibi yapyorum.
Now of course I need to parse this in the checkout component and then I'll do this in
imdi elbette deme bileeninde bu ayrtrmam gerekiyor ve sonra bunu bileeni
componentDidMount
takma yapacam.
I won't use componentDidUpdate or anything like that because whenever I load this component, it will
Gncelleme bileenini veya byle bir ey kullanmayacam nk bu bileeni yklediimde kendini
mount itself,
takacak.
there is no way I can route to it without it being mounted again because it's not nested in some other
Baka bir sayfada veya baka bir eyde i ie gemi olmad iin tekrar monte edilmeden
page or anything like that.
ona gidebilmenin hibir yolu yoktur.
Now in there I will want to use the code you saw before to extract the query parameters. I'll create a new
veya baka bir arama Perens kurucusu olarak adlandrdm yeni bir sabiti tedavi edeceim.
constant which I'll name query where I used the URLSearchParams constructor,
imdi burada, sorgu parametrelerini ayklamak iin grdnz kodu kullanmay isteyeceim; burada Querrey'ye d
pass this.props.location.search which includes the ? and so on but with URL search
Bu pervanenin, soru iaretini ve benzeri eleri ieren yer aramasn gein, ancak nerede olduunuzu Peronist'te
purpose, I can basically extract that.
arayacam temelde onu ayklayabiliyorum.
Then I'll add a new ingredients object here because I want to store an ingredients object in this form
Sonra burada yeni bir madde nesnesi ekleyeceim, nk nesneyi devlette bulunduunuz ekliyle
here, in the state and then I will use for let param of query.entries
saklamak ve ierikleri depolamak istiyorum ve Querrey'nin Param Parametresi iin izin vereceim.
as you learned, to loop through the different queryParams and I said that
Arkadanz Querrey ebeveynleri ve ben ayr dng renirken.
each entry will have this format, the key like salad and then the value like one.
Her girdi, bu biime sahip olacak, anahtar satmak gibi bir anahtara sahip olacak ve deeri de bir tane gibi olacak.
Now of course I want to turn this into this object format so I will simply say ingredient param element
ve bu madde nesne Shippy Q'ya eit olan sadece bir isim olan Param eleman 0 esini syleyeceim.
0 which is just a name like this, which is then used as a property name and add it to that ingredient
imdi elbette bu nesneyi formatna evirmek istiyorum, bu nedenle sadece
object should be equal to
bir mlk ad olarak kullanlan Ve imdi iyi gelir -
And now comes to value which is just param element one, this value, and we can convert this into a
yalnzca Param eleman bir deeri vardr ve bunu art ekleyerek bir sayya dntrebiliriz.
number by adding a plus
Ve elbette burada bu javascript nesnesini kullanarak maddeler bulunmaldr.
and of course there should be ingredients here using this javascript object.
imdi bu yapldktan sonra bu kmeyi aracam ve
Now once this is done I can call this set state and hopefully successfully set my ingredients to the
umarm benim malzemelerimi yarattm malzemelere baaryla ayarlayp buradan karabilirim.
ingredients I created and extracted here.
Kurtaralm ie yarayp yaramayacan grmyor.
Let's save this, let's see if it works,
Elle deitirirsem iyi grnr.
looks pretty good. If I now manually change
Diyelim ki, sorguyu kardmz ve baarl bir ekilde lasat parametresinde 2 2 olduunu syledi.
let's say the cheese to 2 in the query parameter, we extract and load this successfully.
imdi, sorguyla verileri iletebiliyoruz Perens, tabii ki byk bir ilerleme kaydediyor.
So now we're able to pass the data with queryParams, a huge advancement of course.
Bir sonraki kii veri ile ilgili alalm.